<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Converging Infinity</title><link>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/</link><description>Find Yourself Starting Back</description><atom:link href="https://blog.autumnrain.cc/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2024 &lt;a href="mailto:"&gt;kat&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 08:08:35 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Awakening and Apophenia</title><link>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/awakening-and-apophenia/</link><dc:creator>kat</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I stand before you, five months after my last post. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a sense, not much has changed. Things have kept moving.  I've obtained my motorcycle license, I've started talking to someone (an angel of the moon, no less :3), and I've broken free of a false maze. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember when I initially built this blog almost a year and a half ago now(!). There hasn't been much posting on it, and it's mostly because as it turns out, I have a life.... and probably ADHD, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For updates, I've gone to girlmoding permanently now. My voice betrays me at a moment's notice, my form a work-in-progress, but I will neither crumple nor submit to sleepers' beliefs of whether or not I even exist. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not for them to decide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For better or worse, I've cut down some of my social media presence due to culture clashes. In one of them, I'm out of the age bracket that culture is formulated by, so I'm pushed away by the diaspora therein. It's not that I'm not wanted, it's that I can't provide them much interest, and I'm also not really interested in pure outrage all of the time anyways. However, I also quite dislike getting tone-policed for showing a degree of bitterness around subjects like blatant human rights violations, things affecting trans care, the rising tide of anti-trans rhetoric, et cetera. Talk only works if you can back it up with action and participation; There are precious few who do so, and I've reached a certain limit with those who cannot. If you're on that site, you're still welcome to contact me, but until I can regain my energy and become confident in building a community over there, I'm on hiatus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm still writing my VtM campaign. It's going well, but I've pivoted to writing a one-shot and developing an 'ephemeral codex' for the lore noobs in the group. I intend to introduce the group to Mage down the line, but revealing much more would be spoiler territory for those in it (hi nerds!!! :3). It also makes for fun banter between pulls when we're raiding ("roll me Dex + Martial Arts, nerd!").&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The heavy stuff still weighs so. One thing I realize (and friends corroborate) about the burnout, the breakups, the bitterness, is that things don't 'heal' so much as they become easier to navigate. The burnout is mostly gone, now, but I still get the occasional backlash from time-to-time. The bleeding has stopped, but now I have faded scars and emotional soft spots. 
An example presents itself after I told them my upcoming class schedule, where my parents mentioned how little pride I give myself in doing the hard things, and leading through example, and how proud of me they were that I was pushing through everything. I am trying to be my best self; and that self requires that I push back against the tide of people and structures unable, or outright refusing to see me for the woman I am. I don't give myself much praise, but it made me realize, after some tears, that despite my flaws, my neuroses, my mistakes, I can still build something worthwhile. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I will continue to push back against the six million gallons of ignorance, build the life I want to live, seek the knowledge I hunger for, and advocate for our rights and futures as trans folks. I seek more of our art to hear, see, experience, and feel. I want more of our knowledgebase in my brainspace.
I want our ability to live as ourselves to be secured. 
I will not yield. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stand your ground, Hold Your Color ❤️&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>forward movement</category><category>ramblings</category><guid>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/awakening-and-apophenia/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Six Seconds</title><link>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/six-seconds/</link><dc:creator>kat</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://blog.autumnrain.cc/images/paradiso.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;p&gt;March 31st. International Trans Day of Visibility. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 15th one, to be precise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we go into the weeds, I want to make a slight callback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've mentioned before that I've always wanted to make an &lt;a href="https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/encroaching-darkness/"&gt;immersive sim&lt;/a&gt;, but in that post I felt like I did a bad job of describing what, exactly, preempts me from doing so, outside of the thousands of systems needing to snap in place late into development and the fact that I am one person. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact of the matter is that I'm not a great writer. I feel I have no writing voice, especially not for fiction. Yet, I write anyways, inspired by works and authors of the past, in hopes that one day I'll be good enough to make my own stories worth telling. Until then, I'm enamored with the imagery of the scarlet stepped pyramid of the Eastern Seaboard Fission Authority, reminded by the echoes of a linguistic Metavirus, and personally involved in the actual allegorical basis of two different-colored pills in my own way&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/six-seconds/#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, that's not the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In training a skill, one must practice&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href="https://xkcd.com/285/"&gt;[citation needed]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. A skill not practiced holds little practical capability, where it generally fades away into the neuronic noise, overwritten by pathways not beset by one's wont to preserve that little-used skill. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, I have been practicing, and obviously the starting results haven't been &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; per se, but I wanted to describe one of the biggest frustrations I've had when doing my research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't remember who said it first, since I know it's not original, but I can't find the reference anymore - The idea of cyberpunk media in terms of its temporal placement being 'six seconds into the future'. 
I like to envision that future as still rooted in the old structures of modern reality, but of course those structures being built atop of with technological enhancement and societal decay. The problem with this statement is adequately defining it, but I almost see it as allegorical: 'six seconds' is far away to consider it being 'future' enough to describe it as speculative, but close enough to not be in the realm of settings akin to space operas. &lt;em&gt;Deus Ex&lt;/em&gt; (2000) does this really well in my opinion, but it's a bit of an archaic example, mostly due to its age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been kind of a techno pessimist as of late. I love technology but hate where it's going: There's little innovation being done anymore, and generally I have a great dislike for things like streaming services and the modern machine learning buzzword-compliance fad. "Evolve or die" doesn't work if the point of the evolution is to be replaced by some longtermist's wet dream of 'reducing' labor costs by sucking up a lake's worth of water every hundred queries or so to replace programmers, writers, and artists. I have gazed upon wrongs darker than death or night... iconoclastic gods toying with reality in pursuit of the mundane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless, that pessimism has extended pretty far into my existence, politics, and social media generally. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything is stained the same color: Surge pricing at a Wendy's&lt;sup id="fnref:2"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/six-seconds/#fn:2"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, politicians attempting to ban gender affirming care nationwide, and the inability for anyone to actually do fuckall about the ongoing climate crisis.
Hell, even &lt;em&gt;COVID-19&lt;/em&gt; is still around and sucks super hard because people don't want to mask the fuck up. It's incredibly depressing. Not to mention, I'd really like to not give some unhinged CEO some idea about how to create another torment nexus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there's hope in the sense that the fiction I write isn't a training manual. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn't take the gift of Apollo to see how things could progress, but cyberpunk traditionally is one part warning, one part allegory, and one part satire of reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hell, Gibson got the details wrong for how much memory a computer might have, but &lt;em&gt;Neuromancer&lt;/em&gt; was written in the 1980s where it was borderline inconceivable to envision more than a few hundred KiBs. I can be wrong, I'm not infallible. And I think the point is, with all of this depressing garbage going on &lt;em&gt;right now&lt;/em&gt;, that I can write a story and hope I'm wrong about the bad things. Living a trans existence &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; means that, when we reach those six seconds, that those predictions come to pass in a positive manner instead of creating the very dystopian hellscape I describe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for that modern trans existence, I've been blessed with support from my mother, but cursed with the bitterness from many others around me. I'm incredibly lucky that I have the supportive friends, family, coworkers I do have, but I recognize that's a privilege that many trans folks don't have. Whilst I'm no stranger to being accosted in the street, getting slurs thrown at me, constantly disrespected by people entirely unable to show compassion or envision what being trans is actually like, I hope that those folks that need support more than I do are willing to see this and reach out - I'm willing to listen to your woes, be your friend when others won't be, and empathize with your struggles. You are wanted, you are loved, and I'm happy you're here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy Trans Day of Visibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the word 'Premarin' means anything to you, you nailed it. &lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/six-seconds/#fnref:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please do not gas the price of my sandwich as I'm ordering it. &lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/six-seconds/#fnref:2" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>tdov</category><guid>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/six-seconds/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Another Appreciation for RSS</title><link>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/happy-bday-RSS/</link><dc:creator>kat</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Got a bit of a quick one for you today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On March 15th, 1999, RSS was initially released to the world on the Netscape.com portal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, I wrote about RSS as a part of an experiment where I tried to find one cool thing weekly.
I failed at that experiment, but I think it was a good experiment. It's a shame it had to be on substack first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now, I revive that post somewhat in an in-depth appreciation for RSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy birthday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Vaguely Technical: RSS format&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RSS uses XML formatting to describe a feed and its items. Whilst XML causes some developers to get the thousand-yard stare, myself somewhat included, I have used it before with little issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite creation was an RSS feed reading bot for News and Podcasts I used for an XMPP server. It just fit right in and it posts to some MUCs we have setup. We love newsbot in this house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give an example of RSS' XML format, here's an entry from my &lt;a href="https://infosec.town"&gt;infosec.town&lt;/a&gt; account:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="code"&gt;&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;item&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;title&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;![CDATA[Build target: _katerina 🏳️‍⚧️ renotes]]&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;link&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;https://infosec.town/notes/9qi6i8sau4gzl45f&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;/link&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;guid&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;https://infosec.town/notes/9qi6i8sau4gzl45f&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;/guid&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;pubDate&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tue,&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;05&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Mar&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;2024&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;16:58:57&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;GMT&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;/pubDate&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;content:encoded&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;![CDATA[ &amp;lt;span class="renote_note without_img"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;hr&amp;gt;Jerry Bell :verified_paw: :donor: :verified_dragon: :rebelverified:​(@jerry@infosec.exchange) says:                        &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="cp"&gt;    Sites available&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="cp"&gt;    ❌Facebook&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="cp"&gt;    ❌instagram&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="cp"&gt;    ✅Infosec.exchange&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="cp"&gt;    ]]&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;/content:encoded&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;/item&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is certainly not the cleanest example, but it's still pretty simple. This describes a repost on my account, with a link, publish date, and encoded content.
If I were using a feed reader like feedly or something, I could see all of my posts in chronological order, including reposts, in one feed. I could do that for other accounts, too!
I could have a mixed feed of webcomics, News, and social media posts in one app. &lt;a href="https://feedly.com/"&gt;Feedly&lt;/a&gt;, as mentioned prior is a popular option, but I'm pretty attached to using local apps in my terminal and such.
The tags, as far as I'm aware, are generally pretty standard across RSS versions (though things like ATOM have some extra fields added that break compatibility somewhat). This makes making things that use it &lt;em&gt;incredibly easy&lt;/em&gt; to develop, such as the aforementioned RSS feed reading bot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Social&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To appreciate RSS, one must contemplate how often they interact with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an avid podcast listener, I interact with it pretty much daily. Whilst apps like Google Podcasts exist&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/happy-bday-RSS/#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, I tend to veer towards the open-source. For a long time I used gPodder on PC, but for want of synchronization and modernity, I moved over to KDE's Kasts on Desktop and Laptops, and Antennapod for mobile. I sync my subscriptions with a nextcloud instance. It treats me pretty well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty much all of my podcasts have easily-found RSS feeds, and in the worst scenarios (like podcasts only hosted on Apple podcasts for some reason?) I can use something like &lt;a href="https://getrssfeed.com/"&gt;Get RSS Feed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does my podcast behavior matter? Well, it's a form of curation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can self-curate pretty much any content I wish so long as it has an RSS feed. News sites, blogs, podcasts. I have control and authority over what I can read. This is &lt;em&gt;incredibly powerful&lt;/em&gt; for ingesting content.
At one point, even Facebook and Twitter had RSS feeds. Those things are gone now, but many Fediverse platforms support it, and the protocol is primarily chronological, making self-curation easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the modern era, we've become incredibly reliant on algorithmic news feeds to deliver us headlines and content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I propose that with RSS slowly regaining its appeal, that we cultivate a new era of web syndication. RSS does the job well, is used constantly in various types of places like blogs and podcasts, and is interoperable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Reader might be dead, algorithms might have made decisions for us in the past, but self-curation and interoperability are incredibly powerful. Not to mention, for me, it feels more human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you, RSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/12/google-podcasts-dies-april-2024-youtube-music-migration-tool-goes-live/"&gt;Oops! My bad! Add it to the graveyard.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/happy-bday-RSS/#fnref:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>RSS</category><category>tech</category><guid>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/happy-bday-RSS/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 07:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Estradiol Soundsystem</title><link>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/estradiol-soundsystem/</link><dc:creator>kat</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://blog.autumnrain.cc/images/ess.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;p&gt;I honestly expected this to be A) sooner, and B) before the politics post, but neither happened so here we are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start, the blog has been reskinned and the template swapped. The blog should have proper opengraph media previews now! This has been a small but frustrating issue to work through since adding them on bootstrap 4 didn't make them want to play nice with fediverse platforms in particular, and since that's my most likely posting location these days, I wanted them to at least &lt;em&gt;look&lt;/em&gt; pretty. It's also &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; faster since it's not loading a 4k image as the wallpaper (an admittedly rookie mistake), and I'm still thinking about transferring the blog to gitlab or some kind of VPS. This does somewhat mean I need to figure out a new comment system for it, but I'm looking into the viability of the mastodon comments system plugin for Nikola, or the cactus comments system, but I'm not sure how I like having guest accounts comment freely (that typically leads to spam). Or maybe I'll write my own. Who knows. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The major tie-up with the opengraph tags is that I'm more mad that I spent the time on a template, just for a swap to bootblog4 to end up solving most of my issues. I'd like those hours back, please. But no, time moves ever forward. Also I should've just used bootblog4 as a base in the first place, but I digress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like I'm still developing myself as a person, and I think my various writings reflect that. I've recovered a lot from my burnout and am ready to approach things in a more sane and healthy manner. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've started HRT injections in February... Those who know me will know I've been on HRT for a bit but generally not getting much progress in pill form, so we've moved forward a little more. To celebrate this momentous achievement, I accidentally made a fucking awesome album cover and, almost immediately, regretted doing so because of my upcoming foray into music. 
Regardless, doing so made me think about my existence as a trans woman more, because whilst moving towards injections was a MASSIVE thing for me and was worth celebrating, I've had some issues with engaging with family members, now former friends, etc as a result of transitioning in the first place, mostly stemming from political positioning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I'm frustrated, annoyed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I elected to write about some other political frustrations and it went through a few iterations. I can't say the writing is particularly amazing, but it's better than the first draft &lt;em&gt;for sure&lt;/em&gt;. I'm intending to rely less on anecdotes for the next ones, as well, and making them a little more cohesive. So ultimately that's the gist of it all - writing about my perspective on the political system as my whole self&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/estradiol-soundsystem/#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They're all going to take some time, so don't expect a static schedule, but I'll try to aim for like one a month, probably, assuming life doesn't spit in my face again, amongst other things. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone has any comment system suggestions, constructive feedback, etc, it's certainly welcome! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll note quickly that my critique of $political_topic is obviously not representative of every group I'm considered a part of... this is me and me alone. If you gotta criticize anyone about these posts, it's gotta be me and me alone, lol. &lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/estradiol-soundsystem/#fnref:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>blog meta</category><category>personal</category><guid>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/estradiol-soundsystem/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 19:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Trials of the Election Year I: Introduction and Social Media Dialogue</title><link>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/TEY2024-1/</link><dc:creator>kat</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Hello! It's been awhile!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have plenty to write about but due to certain... aspects of those prospective posts, I wanted to push this one to the front and engage with those aspects somewhat directly in a separate post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally I don't like to shove politics into things, but at this point I feel like having unvoiced opinions is significantly worse than voicing them at all. Given the nature of this election cycle, I find it's important to touch on things leading up to it in an attempt to vocalize how I feel about things, and channel some frustrations. In addition to that fact, my mere existence is political, and whilst I don't think screaming about things endlessly on social media is particularly productive past a certain point, I find that muzzling myself is going to cause more problems than saying anywhere from little to nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter: The Trials of the Election Year: A US-centric series of posts talking about policy and the modern body politic, all the way throughout the chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make no mistake: I'm not so deluded as to think that my opinions alone should be the law of the land, I am not a political science major, I am not the standard for everyone, and I am certainly not above critique in any manner. I mostly want to stir conversations that I feel need to be had in order to create and engage in dialogue. I'm also aware that these posts probably won't help me make any friends, but I'm willing to accept that risk. Constructive feedback is welcomed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post will primarily cover my observations on social media discourse, particularly in the context of social media, primarily Twitter. If it's not that interesting to you, you can probably skip this one. There's a lot to cover generally, and this one is somewhat banal if for no other reason than to ease into the format. In this instance, it's more anecdotal than future entries will be. A little more casual, if you will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Social Media Dialogue&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, the benefits and limitations therein&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social Media: The overall replacement for forums past 2012, for the most part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was in high school, I had started a twitter account. I don't really remember why I did it, and I don't really think there was a good reason at the time. I had already fallen out of facebook because it wasn't interesting and I was already heavily annoyed with the privacy implications via the &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20110824222403/https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2011/07/case-pseudonyms"&gt;Nym Wars&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20230410125102/https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/social-media/timeline-facebook-s-privacy-issues-its-responses-n859651"&gt;amongst other things&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that twitter was &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; better by any measure, but it didn't have a "real name" policy so it was a lot easier, in my eyes, to use and explore even before I began my transition. I remember finding the infosec community, and becoming infatuated with systems that way. Getting news immediately. Following my favorite musicians, all of that. The problems with twitter's pre-Musk model were numerous, &lt;a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/journalism/2012/11/28/role-social-media-arab-uprisings/"&gt;but the ability to disseminate and gather information quickly was what made it appealing&lt;/a&gt;. For years I engaged with multiple communities, ranging from hackers to OSINT people to retrocomputing folks, learning new things, meeting new people digitally. For a short while, I heavily enjoyed my presence on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then 2020 happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Misinformation, Outrage, and Political Disavowal&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sheer amount of misinformation of the somewhat-still-ongoing coronavirus pandemic, the racial justice protests, and elections really showcases some of the absolute glaring flaws of fast-paced social media discourse. Grifters popping up all over touting ivermectin as a cure for coronavirus symptoms, defenders of the boot, cryptocurrency scams, people 'concerned' about 'optics'&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/TEY2024-1/#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and election denialism. Needless to say, there's a ton to dissect here. The early stages of the pandemic in 2020 strained already-weak systems to the breaking point. Medically, socially, and politically. For this particular instance, I'll focus on the sociopolitical and vaguely technological aspects; It's much more interesting and relevant to how we engage with politics online these days, in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Misinformation, specifically, is a damning condemnation of our modern media landscape, and is the bane of moderation teams and semi-political social media users practically anywhere. It permeates like water into your coffee grounds, and is practically impossible to control if a sufficiently motivated group abuses algorithms or advertising to get what they're touting in front of as many eyes as possible. It's even more miserable when the President at the time is spewing conspiracy theories and grifts himself. This can make judgment calls &lt;em&gt;incredibly difficult&lt;/em&gt;. This continued into 2021 with NFTs, and naturally continues evermore until the dying breath of a production VPS collapses into silence. Tragically, it's incredibly difficult to produce solutions to this problem outside of dismantling algorithms in favor of chronological timelines, for example, but you run into the issues of missing posts and the fact that some people actually like having algorithms around, not to mention that it doesn't even entirely fix the issue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Algorithms have largely a financial incentive and as a direct result, are gamed pretty hard, too. We've reached the point in the media landscape where click prioritization, mass-produced &lt;a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/news/just-five-chatgpt-queries-can-use-16oz-of-water-say-researchers"&gt;water-eating&lt;/a&gt; LLM-generated slop, and search engine optimization cast their shadows heavily and oppressively upon the ever-crowded timelines of social media webapps. Social media is oft an advertising machine, and nothing feeds those dragon-style piles of money like clickthrough rate (stemming largely from clickbait from advertising-based news sites), engagement, and granular data collection (and furthermore, the sale of that granular data at-scale). This toxic combination in the context of politics ultimately results in outrage baiting for advertising dollars and easy political points for election year. This is not to say that all outrage is entirely unwarranted. In fact, I would prefer even outrage than say, pure apathy. Rather, it's more akin to how easily outrage can be redirected to something impermanent: It's incredibly easy to pacify a cause by redirecting social media outrage to something pointless if that outrage could threaten the status quo. The ability to decipher outrage bait versus a legitimate cause is becoming more challenging by the day, and some of that info might not even be real anymore. There's concern in &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; movement about outrage and the effect it has in regards to digesting media. It does not mean we should filter everything out with the precision of a sledgehammer, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the racial justice protests of 2020 were starting up, and even a while before, I remember hearing a lot about biases in technological design. One of the prime examples of this at the time was racial bias in soap dispensers - a &lt;a href="https://reporter.rit.edu/tech/bigotry-encoded-racial-bias-technology"&gt;failure of imagination&lt;/a&gt; attributed to lack of diversity and compassion in the tech industry. I remember the backlash this received, particularly from people who think technology is somehow apolitical in nature. People shutting down conversations because they didn't want to think about the political, social, or similarly economic consequences of what they were building. Or maybe they'd prefer to solve the problem technologically, despite it being innately a human problem that can only realistically be solved by challenging biases and more stringent, inclusive testing for example. For some, it was an immensely uncomfortable&lt;sup id="fnref:2"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/TEY2024-1/#fn:2"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; conversation, but one that needed to be had in order to make tech solutions work for &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, naturally, culminated into a few tech people disavowing any political discourse in their feeds, a common sight even still. The fundamental flaw with this approach, however, is twofold: To start, by filtering out all politics, you could become ignorant to issues plaguing the body politic (i.e. systemic issues in infrastructure) being engaged in dialogue, and additionally, your silence could be (and often is) construed as a political position itself. This is not to say that you should engage in political dialogue in every waking breath (especially because it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; so exhausting), but awareness is step one in resolving political issues of our time. Thus it's my current position that using your tools (blocking, muting, prioritizing certain tags, etc) are probably your best bet at engaging in political discussion in a healthy manner. Asking people to drop certain topics or discourse isn't necessarily going to be productive, either, mostly because it comes across as provocative (and frankly, hostile). More careful selection of sources helps too, but with large language models taking hold and search engines becoming more and more useless, it's becoming a lot harder. More digging will be required if we want to keep discussions generally sane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summation, contemporary social media has fundamental economic and human-related flaws in regards to its design that may even outweigh its benefits. Misinformation, outrage, and ignorance all play a significant part in pitting individuals against each other whilst platforms benefit directly based off of advertising dollars and engagement. Politicians benefit by creating nonsensical culture war outrage bait and scoring easy political points for mostly non-issues, generally partnered with campaign advertisements centered on political opponents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capital is generally only concerned with continuous/infinite growth and consolidation of capital itself. How it fulfills those obligations is generally irrelevant, and, in the context of social media, it all feeds back into itself to create a vitriolic harmony of internet brain poisoning, algorithmic game theory, political apathy, and the inability for the average person to envision what better systems would actually look like. Even in the face of this, there is no perfect social media site, and no matter what platforms or protocols you're on now, you should engage with the movements you believe in, especially if you're pretty bitter about it. You might not change minds, but you'll have made a point and like I said earlier, awareness is step one in solving the problems of our time. Rational conversation is another step. Maybe then, we'll find synthesis in understanding, build those better systems, and make them worth engaging in further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protests are &lt;em&gt;supposed&lt;/em&gt; to be disruptive! That's why they have any potential in working at all! &lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/TEY2024-1/#fnref:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst I agree that online politics are oft a draining activity, one's blissful ignorance shouldn't be above the ability to make things actually work, be it politics, technology, etc. &lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/TEY2024-1/#fnref:2" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>politics</category><category>social media</category><category>TEY</category><guid>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/TEY2024-1/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 23:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Become unstoppable, lest you get caught in the torrential light...</title><link>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/F2023/</link><dc:creator>kat</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;So, this is it, the end of 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is that... another post before another month passes us by? Mark &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; on the calendar. Granted, it's short, but too much of what's been going on has been just terribly mundane. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a lot of work ahead of me until New Years' so let me kind of elaborate on the nonsense and we can start working towards the goals, one step at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;The Past (Month)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;wanted&lt;/em&gt; to get some kind of music out this month; Unfortunately this is not happening as my creative endeavors have mostly been visual. My partner requested an art piece for the holidays, and thus I obliged and attempted to make it the pinnacle of my recent works. I feel like I did an okay job (that I still want to improve upon) despite the short notice and stress of attempting to make it as good as possible within my skill level, which is still growing the more I do the thing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have picked up some side work for a friend additionally that I cannot speak publicly about, but I'm hoping it leads to something interesting and mentally stimulating. A good time to stretch my reverse engineering skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of this, December's been an exhausting affair. I've been sick twice at least and I want to avoid taking too many days off from here on: Things. &lt;strong&gt;Must&lt;/strong&gt;. Continue. Moving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Now&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm pretty much swamped with work until the second week of January where I can start &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; cooking. Focus: get through the rest of the week and then some with my sanity, sleep, etc intact. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which pretty swiftly leads me unto...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Future&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Per &lt;a href="https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/tmef/"&gt;Time Moves Ever Forward&lt;/a&gt;, my primary objectives have not changed. Things must continue. Everything will fit into place; It &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; to, even if the end result is a little scuffed. Look forward to the results of boredom until then, because after this week, a lot of things slow down to a crawl. The latter half of the year is a trial in and of itself, such is the pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I am working on a new blog theme that achieves parity with the &lt;a href="https://autumnrain.cc"&gt;Main Site&lt;/a&gt;, and does so easily with all future versions of it, regardless of whatever iterative properties those versions might contain. This is, however, going to take a hot minute as past blog posts have certainly made clear at this stage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;/// REITERATOR&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, there's something to be said about wanting to be the best person one can be. This year alone was a struggle; The depression, the burnout, the 'generally being too broke to live' shit. 
Now, after the majority of my misery has passed, there's still a lot of work I need to do, but I move forward with vision, purpose, and a sense of self. I have reaffirmed my existence to myself. I must press on, despite the god-awful hand I've been dealt. From all the staring into the void I've done, from all the hard-learned lessons from this personally fucking awful year, I have the following words on offer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Become unstoppable, lest you get caught up in the torrential light of crystalline stasis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~Kat&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>blog meta</category><category>dev</category><category>ops</category><category>projects</category><guid>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/F2023/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Time Moves Ever Forward</title><link>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/tmef/</link><dc:creator>kat</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;:'3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted more posts out more frequently but that sure didn't happen lol. This one's gonna be a bit more rambly so you can probably skip it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be balanced, I am still working on things. My GPU started to eat shit so I had to replace that. Unfortunately, I can't stress it out too hard, as I've realized the horror of having my PC case be too old for modern cooling standards, so &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; I'm doing the whole thing. Fuck it. The unfortunate side effect of this is that I have to wait a little longer to do my art again since I'm waiting on my parts to arrive. As of writing, in November, the GPU is installed, and the CPU and Motherboard are ordered. My case, memory, and cooler will be ordered next paycheck, and storage is on the list as well, but for later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is that I'm no longer getting the graphics artifacting and flickering, which tells me that it wasn't just a driver issue, and that the GPU was indeed dying. I will have to change parts of my workflow so the 3D components of the art isn't as intense, which I'm OK with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This does mean that all of my major purchases are donezo, for now, and thus I can prepare for school in earnest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I'm out of my depression rut, thanks to a couple of people who are super kind and fun to hang out with (:3), I can look back at the effects objectively; Things are looking up now, but I expect there to be more, lesser roadblocks in the future. That's OK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the time period of October 2022-June/July 2023 (and even extending a bit into September), the depression absorbed my entire life, and whilst I could get things done, to say I could function was another thing entirely. Whilst I generally dislike spotify for various reasons, I think my listening time on my wrapped and the scrobbles on last.fm heavily reflect that time period, where I just kinda existed for weeks on end, not really being able to feel, listening to my depression music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That dark time has passed, and my motivation is somewhat returned. I'm still burnt out a little, but I can at least look at code again without wanting to throw up, which is a good sign. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current objectives: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish infrastructure projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prepare for school&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get some music out at some point&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forge a better future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving on, I will note that my general social media presence is pretty much dead; Obviously I like the fediverse for various reasons, but I struggle to interact with it because I guess I miss having a circle of folks to interact with, which I don't really have anymore as a direct result of Twitter dissipating, in addition to the social anxiety I feel. Overall, however, I still think a protocol is ideal vs a platform when regarding social media. This being said, I will not be touching bluesky, for example, with a ten-foot (≈3m) lead pole, mostly because it's heavily moderation-resistant and also has Jack Dorsey's involvement in some fashion. After everything I've seen, I think I'm OK with avoiding platforms and protocols he's involved in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this to say that I'm trying to post more from here on, I just don't really have the feel for it yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the blog in and of itself, I'm working on a new theme to achieve parity with my main site, but I'm not sure how I want to handle it this time. Skinning bootstrap4 last time was... fine? But it doesn't seem to support the meta tags I need it to, and adding them in is like, somewhat haphazard since I haven't yet found the areas where they even actually get added, which is somewhat frustrating. Solution: develop my own theme; Caveats: time sink. Will have to think about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also I'm a little older now. Weirdly enough, I got a spike of website traffic on my birthday. Not sure what could've caused that. If you're looking at my blog and was a part of that uhhh welcome! and I'd love to hear from you because I'm so confused about where the hitspike came from, and why it was on my birthday of all days. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expect a follow up when I'm less rambly :3&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>blog meta</category><category>dev</category><category>ops</category><category>projects</category><guid>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/tmef/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Prelude to Synchronization</title><link>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/prelude-to-sync/</link><dc:creator>kat</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Autumn's here, and that means it's time to iterate harder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typically, I have avoided posting what I do at all outside of a specific thing due to a perceived lack of interest, but Months are actually considerable periods of time when you're doing a lot of waiting, and a lot has been happening recently. From a blog authorship perspective, I'm more realizing at this stage that I just shouldn't care about constantly posting actual interesting things, since that was the pre-switch format in the first place. I simply do not think I'm cut out for content creation in that way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monthly format as of current was actually unintentional: I was between jobs and spiraling pretty hard when I was making those posts. Now the situation has evolved. I am working, but I'm also trying to go back to school, I'm still working on a few projects, and I'm still mostly playing catch-up. My mental energy is definitely pretty low almost all of the time. This being said, however, I believe I have reached a stage where I can start posting somewhat more regularly, even if it's not the most interesting thing in the world. I would generally point out how completely uninteresting I think I am, but I will leave that determination up to the reader. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a fun thing, a couple weeks ago I installed Gentoo on one of my aging laptops and realized the horror and monotony of compiling the GNOME desktop environment on a &lt;a href="https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/products/sku/95443/intel-core-i57200u-processor-3m-cache-up-to-3-10-ghz/specifications.html"&gt;2C4T chip from seven years ago&lt;/a&gt;. Needless to say, I stopped that after awhile and just went with &lt;a href="https://awesomewm.org/"&gt;Awesome&lt;/a&gt;, which I had never tried before and I actually enjoy using. I've been customizing and configuring the machine between sleep and shifts, so the total amount of time I've thrown into it is like maybe a weekend. Though the machine was practically functional after the first couple hours post-install, it was still super fidgety due to the lack of front-ends and etc. I elected, additionally, to customize the bootloader despite the fact that I find it more or less unnecessary - I had actually never done it before and it was &lt;em&gt;somewhat&lt;/em&gt; painless except for one absolutely annoying thing: grub hates most of the fonts I throw at it, and it looks... dire. I am looking for some fonts to throw at it that aren't totally butchered by &lt;code&gt;grub2-mkfont&lt;/code&gt; but it's frankly been taking more time than I really want to throw at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an aside, I have swapped to &lt;a href="https://opentofu.org/"&gt;OpenTofu&lt;/a&gt; for provisioning now that it's available, and I'm pleased that my previous TF files are just drop-in, for now. I look forward to see where it goes from here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the Gentoo laptop, I had another go at installing OpenBSD on a VM because the last time I did, it was quirky and on hardware that was incredibly aged. This was fine, actually,  but it wasn't really usable as a proper client machine at the time. The main thing I learned from it was that the install is easier than I remember and XFCE is actually super easy to customize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have some things to do, namely some blog customization stuff (I'm trying to figure out a way to add fields in some areas which isn't super hard, but I want it broken out to a markdown meta header...), I have a laptop I'm eyeing to replace my ever-aging Thinkpad T460 as my main "go box" for school, and I'm still dinking around with the Jabber protocol, albeit slowly. I'm also trying to decide whether or not I should make a new theme for both my website and blog (for parity) since it was about this time last year that I updated it. As such, a follow-up will be forthcoming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay warm out there.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>blog meta</category><category>dev</category><category>ops</category><category>projects</category><guid>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/prelude-to-sync/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Optical Simulacra, Changing Perspectives</title><link>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/optical-simulacra/</link><dc:creator>kat</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Finally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting the spare time to write has been generally pretty challenging. Work itself generally eats up my entire weekend, but I actually got out early today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working third shift and permanently detonating my sleep schedule has given me a bizzare perspective. I'm one of those people who tends to go on really, &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; long walks to get some exercise and reset myself, and doing it at three in the morning adds onto the weirdness. Put simply, the world just isn't designed to operate at night. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in that silence there are still things that reveal themselves. As an example, I rather like the night sky, what little of it can be seen from my neck of the woods. For a long time, I wished to do astrophotography. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modern phone cameras are... interesting. I happen to have a Google Pixel 6 as my daily driver, and overall the phone has treated me well as... my phone. Very rarely do I take pictures with it, because the camera is oft an added bonus, not my make-or-break feature. 
This being said, of course the first thing I do with it is take some pictures of various things, including but not limited to, cats, flowers, and autumn leaves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having had the phone for a bit and being up at ohgodthirty, I elected to take one of my walks. The route is pretty contrived, but it passes near a couple of cell phone towers. So as I pass by one, I take a picture of it flashing, in the ever-lasting silence of the night. After I let the phone do the long exposure, I review the image. I will not be posting the image for various reasons, but overall: the night sky glistens with the stars in the sky, the tower glows with the bright red of its beacons, and I have this... godawful feeling mixed with awe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that I can take pictures at night isn't what bothers me... I guess it's more that the image feels phony. I, with the convenience of modern processing, have just taken a picture that probably was barely possible with the mobile hardware, 5-10 years ago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allow me to explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When looking at a real, modern camera™, there are several components absolutely necessary to take an image. First, you have your camera sensor, generally comprised of tiny capacitors (if you're stuck in CCD land), or tiny photodiodes and transistors, and you have your lens. The lens is the major thing here, because for me this is why this image feels fake: A phone essentially has to emulate, with the best of its ability, a full optical assembly. This can only realistically be done with a &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/how-do-smartphone-cameras-work/"&gt;lens stack in tandem with software processing&lt;/a&gt;, and whilst raw images are possible at 1x from &lt;a href="https://hoagonsight.com/the-pixel-7-cameras-overprocessing-and-image-distortion-problems-why-they-occur/"&gt;certain anecdotes&lt;/a&gt;, it appears that the Pixel 6 itself tends to overprocess anything beyond that. Which is... frankly kind of an issue when you're using supposedly &lt;a href="https://www.tomsguide.com/reviews/google-pixel-6"&gt;one of the best cameras on the market&lt;/a&gt;. I will take this opportunity to say that it's not innately a 'bad camera'-- Moreso that the processing is definitely present, and I've noticed it more the more images I've shot with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So already, an SLR camera is a simulacrum of an optic nerve, but adding layers ontop, we have a &lt;em&gt;simulacrum of a simulacrum&lt;/em&gt;. Yes, this conjunction of words feels like utter nonsense (especially because, despite the fact that I have indeed read &lt;em&gt;Simulacra and Simulation&lt;/em&gt; by Jean Baudrillard, he thought people were taking the orders too seriously so it's difficult to take the source text too seriously as a result of that), but it's given me a lot to think about. In a sense, it seemed a lot like everything around me was stained the same color-- That everything around me was fake and ephemeral; We already live in a world where LLMs have poisoned practically everything, and 'AI art' models (GANs?) have finally started making perceptible images, at the cost of being really shitty to artists trying to make a living... as a result of that, this feeling didn't go away, literally at all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So naturally, I dug up a film camera from my late stepfather's things, and am being lent a DSLR. At first I just had the film camera with some Ilford HP5+, but the digital camera came into being when I realized how completely unforgiving film is to learn on, which I actually like and am still using it for. But I can refine my skill more if I have, frankly, a cheaper method of learning. Enter: &lt;a href="https://www.nikonusa.com/en/nikon-products/product-archive/dslr-cameras/d60.html"&gt;The Nikon D60&lt;/a&gt;. It isn't full frame, but I don't mind at all. As you can see down below, with the image of the cat, it takes a pretty decent picture still!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://autumnrain.cc/images/DSC_0037.JPG" width="500" alt="Master Samwise, an orange and white cat, after eating some grass" style="align: center;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people like the convenience of the modern smartphone, and that's totally OK, but I think I'll take the D60 around with me for awhile, and take some pictures that, at the least, feel just that &lt;em&gt;tiny bit&lt;/em&gt; more real. Even if there's a little bit more effort involved.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>hobbies</category><category>photography</category><category>projects</category><category>ramblings</category><guid>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/optical-simulacra/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 09:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>At the Edge</title><link>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/at-the-edge/</link><dc:creator>kat</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Awful month. Terrible. Zero stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END: Read On...--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good news first:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What little I've managed to get done has been on the blog, primarily, since I would like it to actually look nice and function properly. I'm still working on that, but the links at the top should be a little bit better when they're active rather than losing their properties.... although it's been done with the precision of a rubber mallet for the time being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is now a link back to my main site in the navbar, a common and fair critique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything is nice and tidy now with the new domain I bought recently. The blog is on a subdomain for now. The keen amongst you may note that the RSS feed redirects. Everything on that should be OK due to aliasing, but if it doesn't actually do the redirecting I'll see what I can do about that, or I may just put out posts about the update so people can update their subscriptions accordingly.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jabber-side, I've been dinking about with an XMPP/Matrix bridging system, but there are issues. &lt;a href="https://www.process-one.net/blog/matrix-protocol-added-to-ejabberd/"&gt;ejabberd doesn't support native bridging those protocols in their community edition yet&lt;/a&gt;, and I'm patiently waiting for that support to finally drip down from the enterprise edition. I.... don't really have a concrete solution for bridging either yet, let alone with E2EE, and it appears that there were some.... disagreements between both parties in the past. This being said, group chats may still work fine, but I haven't really had a huge amount of time to work with it yet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now time for the bad news. If you're not interested in hearing it, you've already reached the end of the blog post. Thanks for reading! If you are interested, here's the sitrep:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, blog meta. I have not been able to get the substack shit off of the platform yet. It's happening, but it's gonna have to be over time, unless I get a day where I don't have anything going on and I'm not totally wiped out from work or whatever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm on the edge of another depression spiral, and whilst the piling on of everything all at once is terrible and contrived, I think I may be able to push through if I focus on my objectives... some of which have to change now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall I've had a pretty shit year and some change, and I would LOVE it if it stopped doing that now. I know that's not how it really works, but my face can only take so much pavement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;♫ : &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=adbfJTd717E"&gt;enter shikari - satellites* *&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>ramblings</category><guid>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/at-the-edge/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 10:43:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>