<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Converging Infinity</title><link>https://kautumnrain.github.io/</link><description>Find Yourself Starting Back</description><atom:link href="https://kautumnrain.github.io/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2023 &lt;a href="mailto:"&gt;kat&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 09:30:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The Status Update Zone</title><link>https://kautumnrain.github.io/posts/the-status-update-zone-July-7th/</link><dc:creator>kat</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://kautumnrain.github.io/images/gestalt1.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;p&gt;The title says it all, basically. I dunno how often these will even be necessary, but I've definitely put myself in a corner with how I'm handling the actual blogging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I'm working on getting my old substack content off of the platform and put here. Once this is done, it'll be under the 'digest-archive' category. It is far
past time I stopped relying on that platform for hosting any of my content. The posts will be properly backdated, and all links will be replaced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been roughly a year since I tried to do a weekly arrangement of interesting things, and since then, 
I've burnt out probably three times over and have gone through multiple life-changing events.  I'm slowly getting my groove properly again, 
but I'm still finding it pretty difficult to do things efficiently as of yet. Recovery has been... challenging. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although some things, including some inconsistent applications of certain CSS frameworks on the static HTML
and a haphazard workflow between machines continue to pose some challenges, I don't necessarily find it inconvenient to manage the blog in this way. 
I still find the challenge to be in the writing, and I know I'm not exactly a good author. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been mostly avoiding posting on social media for a hot while, but especially the last couple of weeks... I don't think people want to hear my incessant sadposting about my trivial problems
(and, of course, complaining about it online does nothing for me), so I will keep it to myself, for now. Additionally, with platforms enshittifying extremely fast, I find that navigating all of it,
even with filters, to be incredibly draining. I am not a good litmus test for opinions on these things, so I will not preoffer them here (despite already doing so, basically).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the previous post, I have started on a set of scripts for the Jabber/XMPP protocol. I don't have much more than boilerplate code at present, but I'm hoping to improve the seemingly-dire
script/bot/daemon landscape a little at a time. The major issue appears to be a lack of ready-made API wrappers for some things, but I'm not that worried about it. 
If required, I will design wrappers from scratch, although I cannot promise I will do that consistently. A lot of it has been documentation, research, and planning, 
but I find all three are incredibly important for being able to do anything of note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy (Belated) Pride Month*, and hopefully y'all are living your best lives. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*(Pride Month never stops :P)&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>projects</category><category>ramblings</category><guid>https://kautumnrain.github.io/posts/the-status-update-zone-July-7th/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 07:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Time To Build Is Now</title><link>https://kautumnrain.github.io/posts/reamp/</link><dc:creator>kat</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://kautumnrain.github.io/images/meta.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;p&gt;I tend to say a lot of things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That might seem like an obvious statement to you, but for those that know me well enough, know generally how I feel about the state of the modern web. I am no stranger to loving &lt;a href="https://converginginterests.substack.com/p/second-simple-syndication"&gt;open, interoperable things&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I will admit that generally hating siloes for merely existing is a bit of an old way of thinking, but the game can only be played for so long, and open solutions to modern technological problems require attention in order to be pushed into usable states. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm not a large company. I don't have the millions of dollars of funding to push things into a more usable or covenient state, if those are primary complaints (which we saw with Mastodon). But I will have a little bit of time, a little bit of cash, and a little bit of enthusiasm. To try to build and deploy things. To explore what was lost. To do this in a fun way.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cannot make too many promises now, since I have in the past and I'm realizing that doing so tends to only set me up for failure. What I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; say, is that &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; will come out of it. Even if it's not much, it should be entertaining and interesting, at least for me (:P).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time for talking theoreticals is over; for me, it is time to build. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: Post modified [fixed grammar].&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>dev</category><category>ops</category><category>projects</category><guid>https://kautumnrain.github.io/posts/reamp/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 01:25:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Encroaching Darkness</title><link>https://kautumnrain.github.io/posts/encroaching-darkness/</link><dc:creator>kat</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://kautumnrain.github.io/images/darkness.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;p&gt;I've always wanted to make an immersive sim. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of my earliest exposures to games when I was young were games like &lt;em&gt;Thief&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Deus Ex&lt;/em&gt; that emphasized several ways to resolve an obstacle with additional design for large, believable (but not open, in the modern sense) worlds. The challenge, is that usually immersive sims require hundreds of systems to snap into place late in development, and I am one person with extremely limited time and a crippling coffee addiction running on little sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little while into my first exposure to these kinds of games, I was introduced to Dungeons and Dragons proper after hearing it in passing for a couple years at that point, particularly paired with faint echoes of the satanic panic. Unfortunately, the group fizzled and I had a pretty difficult time getting a group together (Roll20 didn't really exist yet to my knowledge and it certainly wasn't widespread until a hot while later).
My exposure to and interest in TTRPGs up until 2019ish waxed and waned often. I was mostly playing Warhammer 40k until 2015, at which point the game just stopped being fun because of awful players and Games Workshop being generally a nuisance, and thus we swapped to other games like Corvus Belli's Infinity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days, my partner and I engage with a homebrew D&amp;amp;D campaign, but my interest in D&amp;amp;D has waned, and it's obvious Wizards of the Coast cannot be trusted with the OGL, so I have branched out to the World of Darkness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have had EXTREMELY little exposure to WoD, but I &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; played &lt;em&gt;VtM: Bloodlines&lt;/em&gt; (and am somewhat familiar with its particular flavor of Source jank). It's an intriguing setting that I can't believe has bypassed my senses beyond the Source game for this long. It's a world that can be horrifying, bitter, and gruesome, but also heartwarming, intriguing, and at times, absolutely &lt;em&gt;ridiculous&lt;/em&gt;, and I think that's important for making the setting stand out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I'm working out my Immersive Sim writing muscles. Designing a campaign that captures the intriguing, the insane, the hilarious, the horrid, and the inspiring. WoD is an intersection of things, and it cannot be all doom and gloom all the time (unless you're running a campaign like that [I guess]. Are you running a Time of Judgement scenario?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think one of WoD's strengths is that it takes place in $currentTime in $currentWorld, but I wanted something that was familiar, but not the same. A place that I could do the research for and not exactly rely on my own personal interactions with it. Due to my upcoming campaign being an introductory one, I wanted to avoid a massive metropolitan area like Seattle or Chicago. Making the premise has been somewhat the hardest part, but I think the work I'm putting into it will be worth it. I mostly got the idea from someone in friend circle making a joke that I'm essentially taking too far. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven't quite decided how much I want to involve another sourcebook, but if I do decide to implement another character or what-have-you, it'll probably be pretty surface level for this. I believe Demon and Mummy in particular are in dire straits regarding old rules weirdness. If anyone has suggestions on how either book is handled in the 20th Anniversary edition, I'd be curious to hear your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, I shall ponder my next steps.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>gaming</category><category>ramblings</category><category>ttrpg</category><category>WoD</category><guid>https://kautumnrain.github.io/posts/encroaching-darkness/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 11:05:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>On the Perils of 'Everything'</title><link>https://kautumnrain.github.io/posts/on-the-perils-of-everything/</link><dc:creator>kat</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Ah. Scope creep rears its ugly head again. Except... it's by design, for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://kautumnrain.github.io/posts/ramblings-of-a-cryotank/"&gt;Previously&lt;/a&gt;, I mentioned that there may be a post regarding 'everything apps'. In actuality, I described it using the term 'rant', but I think I can structure this in a way that doesn't require a flow of consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For starters, I suppose I should mention that I'm not entirely adverse to people and companies trying to do different things in software. My opinion, however, is that an application or script should do at most three things, lest functionality, usability and sanity be sacrificed for an ever-expanding featureset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;section id="it-s-got-it-all"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;It's Got It All&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the advent of modern-social media, there's been huge pushes to just consolidate and pack entire apps and functions into each other, at the innate cost of usability. Although it's not always so inelegant, this general concept of social media consolidation can be described as an 'everything app'. Apps like WeChat in mainland China specifically come to mind, however I believe the closest possible Western analog is probably the main Facebook social media platform. Being able to send and recieve money, engage with e-commerce (i.e. Marketplace), chat with your friends/coworkers/(oft-disdainful) family members, review whatever place you went to for lunch, etc are all common features of the modern 'Everything App'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="substacking-the-deck"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Substacking the Deck&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 'Ramblings of a Cryotank', I explicitly named Substack, but it's mostly because I have some gripes about how the systems are actually implemented over there, and it also happens to be a really good example of an app attempting to expand its featureset and, of course, doing it poorly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Twitter eating the pavement on-contact with Space Karen and his so-called 'moderation strategy', a lot of folks are trying to escape it, with some of the earliest waves in May and November of 2022 from my observation. As a result of this, you have a lot of replacement apps cropping up or being shifted to. Some people elected to restart blogs again, and that's where Substack comes in and tries to eat up some of that sweet, sweet marketshare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Substack is pretty appealing to someone who doesn't want to deal with any site management in any sense, outside of Adsense (heh) and branding. I certainly understand it; I imagine the vast majority of writers aren't systems administrators, nor would they necessarily want to be (although I would LOVE to be proven wrong), as they'd like to spend more time doing the writing they want to rather than writing code. In its pre-Twitter meltdown incarnation, it was described as mostly an infrastructure provider. The problem with that interpretation, however, is primarily one of moderation. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22196035/substack-moderation-policy-detailed"&gt;Substack is known for its pretty lax moderation policies&lt;/a&gt;, which has, predictably, resulted in the spread of misinformation and a generally-hostile community. So let's just duct-tape twitter-like functionality onto it, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="taking-notes"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Taking Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Substack proceeds to add a microbloggging feature, to fill the Twitter void... with no intentions to have a hand in moderation itself. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.techdirt.com/2023/04/14/substack-ceo-chris-best-doesnt-realize-hes-just-become-the-nazi-bar/"&gt;This article by Mike Masnick&lt;/a&gt; does a pretty good job describing the situation. The primary takeaways regarding moderation are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Free Speech maximalism continues to be total abject failure&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even if it did work, it proves that the moderation policies in place right now cannot be applied evenly across the entire service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, substack was already in pretty rough moderation straits before, but as the techdirt article linked above states, the Notes feature automatically brings Substack closer to being a typical social media platform, and as a result absolutely MUST moderate in order to maintain its revenue stream. It's clear that Substack isn't prepared for what comes with actually being social media in this way, although I guess I can't say I'm really all that surprised, coming from the team that headed &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.techdirt.com/2021/05/21/content-moderation-case-study-kik-tries-to-get-abuse-under-control-2017/"&gt;Kik Messenger&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="other-glaring-instances"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other Glaring Instances&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously Substack isn't the only offender here. Whilst it's useful as a case study for  implementations and moderation failures as a result of those, I think there are even more mundane systems that attempt to shift into another function and fail, or just don't even try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discord's Forum system, for example, is essentially a real-time chat channel disguised as a
replacement for real forums, which it certainly isn't. Forums are usually indexable and slower-moving, which influences the conversation. Certainly a different &lt;em&gt;era&lt;/em&gt; of design, but not necessarily outdated in regards to conveying information. Discord isn't indexable, which means when those servers inevitably shutdown, all info in those forums goes away permanently. The forum format isn't perfect and has its own share of issues (as well as starting some that continued with modern social media), but a real time chat system is hardly an adequate replacement for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook/Meta is also, as mentioned, the closest possible western analog to a WeChat-like app in this market, and as such also suffers from way... WAY too many issues to count in one blog post like this. Privacy debacles, interoperability issues, moderation missteps...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="please-stop-trying-to-make-everything-apps"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Please Stop Trying To Make Everything Apps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem, I think, is that in the ever-fast-moving era of social media, is that we like having less apps to install, it seems. Gone are the days of 'there's an app for that'. There still is an app for it, but it's been consolidated into like three or four of them instead of ten. I'm not saying there aren't benefits to something like that, but it hardly brings about only positive results, and we're going to have to decide whether it's worth it to have only a couple of applications, companies, and people dictating entire functions of our lives, with all of the moderation, privacy, and ad misery involved with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't have too many explicit solutions, but I do think that there is something to be said for single or dual-purpose applications that don't necessarily involve being 'The App' (singular).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For what people can do personally; Make a blog, make a forum, contribute to whatever you think is worthwhile, but remember:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monoculture kills the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description><category>social media</category><category>sociology</category><category>tech</category><guid>https://kautumnrain.github.io/posts/on-the-perils-of-everything/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 22:58:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Logical Progression</title><link>https://kautumnrain.github.io/posts/logical-progression/</link><dc:creator>kat</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;uhhhh whoops! Looks like I accidentally skinned bootstrap4!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm absolutely &lt;strong&gt;NOT DONE&lt;/strong&gt; with customizing this, but I mostly wanted to
get the theme rolling so I had &lt;em&gt;SOME&lt;/em&gt; idea of what I wanted to do. The main
objective to be trying to get somewhat close to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://kautumnrain.neocities.org"&gt;my personal site&lt;/a&gt;,
which I'd say the theme is pretty close to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I'd like to add a sidebar of the most recent posts and an archive
tree. After that, I'm probably done for awhile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me know what you think about all of this!&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>blog meta</category><guid>https://kautumnrain.github.io/posts/logical-progression/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 13:34:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Blog Changes</title><link>https://kautumnrain.github.io/posts/blog-changes/</link><dc:creator>kat</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Check this out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed I have swapped out the theme from &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://themes.getnikola.com/v8/hack/"&gt;hack&lt;/a&gt; to
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://themes.getnikola.com/v8/bootstrap4/"&gt;bootstrap4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm doing it mostly for ease of customization,
but it's becoming incredibly clear that I may just have to do a pure overhaul of most themes.
There are huge 'one-liners' of CSS that make it pretty difficult to modify the theme further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such, this will be a temporary theme until I have the time and energy to bring things into my personal
spec.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automation-wise, I haven't really worked on that yet either, mostly because it's largely dependent on
me settling on a theme, but I might just go ahead and write the pipeline anyhow, since I have to rebuild
the entire project anyways every time I want to post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the theme? Don't care for it? Let me know (mostly because some of this theme might end up in the
real semi-permanent one).&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>blog meta</category><guid>https://kautumnrain.github.io/posts/blog-changes/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 04:34:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ramblings of a Cryotank</title><link>https://kautumnrain.github.io/posts/ramblings-of-a-cryotank/</link><dc:creator>kat</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I'm mostly writing this to take my mind off things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tragically, I'm trying to keep my mind off of not getting
an immediate response from an HR dept about some work, since
self-employment didn't treat me all that well. Learning new
things as much as possible is excellent when the job you have
gives any kind of consistent income, which is not how this has gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I digress, and will build myself a better future as necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nikola's templating system is interesting but I haven't had a huge
amount of time to pick it apart and make my own. Respectfully,
the documentation could be slightly better, but I admit it is perhaps
a personal failing that I don't exactly understand it immediately.
I intend to draw and plan out my theme and throw it up for those
using Nikola as well, assuming I can get it to my liking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a customizable config, of course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The automation with actions seems pretty straightforward, but as an eventuality
I'd like to get this up on an EC2 at some juncture, although staying within
free-tier is probably impossible (understandably).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am still pleased with the move from Substack. Being able to use proper
markdown feels VERY good, and a proper RSS feed is much more appealing
than exploding an inbox. People get enough emails daily as-is.
I know I do, although I will still subscribe to and read them
because I like supporting other writers, too. I would like to give
more details on this in the future. I think Substack is trying to be
many things that it isn't that great at being, and it may tie into
a larger platform-related rant regarding 'everything apps'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The comment system I'm using, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://utteranc.es/"&gt;utterances&lt;/a&gt;, is still pretty nifty to me.
I know not everyone has a github, and I am tempted to throw up a contact
email or something for those that don't partake. We'll see. I definitely
want to throw the effort at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may reuse my favicon or make a new one. My skills over time regarding
2D graphics have definitely improved, and I'd like to make use of them.
They might be stuck in neoy2k-land, but I still find the y2k style super
appealing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I have new, actually attainable goals. Personal tragedy can
be the world's greatest humility machine. The Earth is never as far
away as one thinks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;♫ : Covenant - Call The Ships To Port&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>ramblings</category><guid>https://kautumnrain.github.io/posts/ramblings-of-a-cryotank/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 04:15:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Starting Back</title><link>https://kautumnrain.github.io/posts/starting-back/</link><dc:creator>kat</dc:creator><description>&lt;section id="back-in-a-wip-form"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Back, In A WIP form&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, here we are again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is kind of a continuation from a substack blog...
I decided that despite the blog's many failings, I should try writing again. I'll actually
be throwing a post out over there once I'm finished writing this to prove I'm not just
saying things to say things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted a more elegant (read: deployable) solution, but this was the best I could do in
my current circumstances. The nice thing about this is that I get a proper RSS feed now,
and I can use it for multiple things. Once I get some domains figured out, things just
kinda fall into place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The substack blog was supposed to be a project-specific-esque-learn-everything-always
blog, but it ended up stressing me out more than it needed to, and adding salt into the
wound when things got much worse. One thing I'm recognizing is how awful life-changing
events demotivate me, in all aspects, particularly post-COVID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, I'm trying to make this less like a job, and more like how a blog probably
should be. There'll still be pretty technical stuff going on around here, but since
blogs are suggested by the larger technical diaspora, I'll try to hang on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No speedrunning projects for weekly grinds, no tearing myself apart for burning out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh also; I have yet to customize the blog template, so it's this hyperbasic plain blog
theme. I will get it more inline with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://kautumnrain.neocities.org"&gt;my personal site&lt;/a&gt;
at... some point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'til next time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description><category>iteration</category><category>ramblings</category><guid>https://kautumnrain.github.io/posts/starting-back/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:03:36 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>