<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Converging Infinity (Posts about technology)</title><link>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://blog.autumnrain.cc/categories/cat_technology.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2024 &lt;a href="mailto:"&gt;kat&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 07:37:37 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Another Appreciation for RSS</title><link>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/happy-bday-RSS/</link><dc:creator>kat</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Got a bit of a quick one for you today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On March 15th, 1999, RSS was initially released to the world on the Netscape.com portal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, I wrote about RSS as a part of an experiment where I tried to find one cool thing weekly.
I failed at that experiment, but I think it was a good experiment. It's a shame it had to be on substack first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now, I revive that post somewhat in an in-depth appreciation for RSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy birthday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Vaguely Technical: RSS format&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RSS uses XML formatting to describe a feed and its items. Whilst XML causes some developers to get the thousand-yard stare, myself somewhat included, I have used it before with little issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite creation was an RSS feed reading bot for News and Podcasts I used for an XMPP server. It just fit right in and it posts to some MUCs we have setup. We love newsbot in this house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give an example of RSS' XML format, here's an entry from my &lt;a href="https://infosec.town"&gt;infosec.town&lt;/a&gt; account:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="code"&gt;&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;item&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;title&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;![CDATA[Build target: _katerina 🏳️‍⚧️ renotes]]&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;link&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;https://infosec.town/notes/9qi6i8sau4gzl45f&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;/link&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;guid&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;https://infosec.town/notes/9qi6i8sau4gzl45f&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;/guid&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;pubDate&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tue,&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;05&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Mar&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;2024&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;16:58:57&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;GMT&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;/pubDate&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;content:encoded&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;![CDATA[ &amp;lt;span class="renote_note without_img"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;hr&amp;gt;Jerry Bell :verified_paw: :donor: :verified_dragon: :rebelverified:​(@jerry@infosec.exchange) says:                        &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="cp"&gt;    Sites available&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="cp"&gt;    ❌Facebook&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="cp"&gt;    ❌instagram&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="cp"&gt;    ✅Infosec.exchange&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="cp"&gt;    ]]&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;/content:encoded&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nt"&gt;&amp;lt;/item&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is certainly not the cleanest example, but it's still pretty simple. This describes a repost on my account, with a link, publish date, and encoded content.
If I were using a feed reader like feedly or something, I could see all of my posts in chronological order, including reposts, in one feed. I could do that for other accounts, too!
I could have a mixed feed of webcomics, News, and social media posts in one app. &lt;a href="https://feedly.com/"&gt;Feedly&lt;/a&gt;, as mentioned prior is a popular option, but I'm pretty attached to using local apps in my terminal and such.
The tags, as far as I'm aware, are generally pretty standard across RSS versions (though things like ATOM have some extra fields added that break compatibility somewhat). This makes making things that use it &lt;em&gt;incredibly easy&lt;/em&gt; to develop, such as the aforementioned RSS feed reading bot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Social&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To appreciate RSS, one must contemplate how often they interact with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an avid podcast listener, I interact with it pretty much daily. Whilst apps like Google Podcasts exist&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/happy-bday-RSS/#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, I tend to veer towards the open-source. For a long time I used gPodder on PC, but for want of synchronization and modernity, I moved over to KDE's Kasts on Desktop and Laptops, and Antennapod for mobile. I sync my subscriptions with a nextcloud instance. It treats me pretty well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty much all of my podcasts have easily-found RSS feeds, and in the worst scenarios (like podcasts only hosted on Apple podcasts for some reason?) I can use something like &lt;a href="https://getrssfeed.com/"&gt;Get RSS Feed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does my podcast behavior matter? Well, it's a form of curation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can self-curate pretty much any content I wish so long as it has an RSS feed. News sites, blogs, podcasts. I have control and authority over what I can read. This is &lt;em&gt;incredibly powerful&lt;/em&gt; for ingesting content.
At one point, even Facebook and Twitter had RSS feeds. Those things are gone now, but many Fediverse platforms support it, and the protocol is primarily chronological, making self-curation easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the modern era, we've become incredibly reliant on algorithmic news feeds to deliver us headlines and content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I propose that with RSS slowly regaining its appeal, that we cultivate a new era of web syndication. RSS does the job well, is used constantly in various types of places like blogs and podcasts, and is interoperable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Reader might be dead, algorithms might have made decisions for us in the past, but self-curation and interoperability are incredibly powerful. Not to mention, for me, it feels more human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you, RSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/12/google-podcasts-dies-april-2024-youtube-music-migration-tool-goes-live/"&gt;Oops! My bad! Add it to the graveyard.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/happy-bday-RSS/#fnref:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>RSS</category><category>tech</category><guid>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/happy-bday-RSS/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 07:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>On the Perils of 'Everything'</title><link>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/on-the-perils-of-everything/</link><dc:creator>kat</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Ah. Scope creep rears its ugly head again. Except... it's by design, for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://kautumnrain.github.io/posts/ramblings-of-a-cryotank/"&gt;Previously&lt;/a&gt;, I mentioned that there may be a post regarding 'everything apps'. In actuality, I described it using the term 'rant', but I think I can structure this in a way that doesn't require a flow of consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For starters, I suppose I should mention that I'm not entirely adverse to people and companies trying to do different things in software. My opinion, however, is that an application or script should do at most three things, lest functionality, usability and sanity be sacrificed for an ever-expanding featureset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;section id="it-s-got-it-all"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;It's Got It All&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the advent of modern-social media, there's been huge pushes to just consolidate and pack entire apps and functions into each other, at the innate cost of usability. Although it's not always so inelegant, this general concept of social media consolidation can be described as an 'everything app'. Apps like WeChat in mainland China specifically come to mind, however I believe the closest possible Western analog is probably the main Facebook social media platform. Being able to send and recieve money, engage with e-commerce (i.e. Marketplace), chat with your friends/coworkers/(oft-disdainful) family members, review whatever place you went to for lunch, etc are all common features of the modern 'Everything App'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="substacking-the-deck"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Substacking the Deck&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 'Ramblings of a Cryotank', I explicitly named Substack, but it's mostly because I have some gripes about how the systems are actually implemented over there, and it also happens to be a really good example of an app attempting to expand its featureset and, of course, doing it poorly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Twitter eating the pavement on-contact with Space Karen and his so-called 'moderation strategy', a lot of folks are trying to escape it, with some of the earliest waves in May and November of 2022 from my observation. As a result of this, you have a lot of replacement apps cropping up or being shifted to. Some people elected to restart blogs again, and that's where Substack comes in and tries to eat up some of that sweet, sweet marketshare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Substack is pretty appealing to someone who doesn't want to deal with any site management in any sense, outside of Adsense (heh) and branding. I certainly understand it; I imagine the vast majority of writers aren't systems administrators, nor would they necessarily want to be (although I would LOVE to be proven wrong), as they'd like to spend more time doing the writing they want to rather than writing code. In its pre-Twitter meltdown incarnation, it was described as mostly an infrastructure provider. The problem with that interpretation, however, is primarily one of moderation. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/22/22196035/substack-moderation-policy-detailed"&gt;Substack is known for its pretty lax moderation policies&lt;/a&gt;, which has, predictably, resulted in the spread of misinformation and a generally-hostile community. So let's just duct-tape twitter-like functionality onto it, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="taking-notes"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Taking Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Substack proceeds to add a microbloggging feature, to fill the Twitter void... with no intentions to have a hand in moderation itself. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.techdirt.com/2023/04/14/substack-ceo-chris-best-doesnt-realize-hes-just-become-the-nazi-bar/"&gt;This article by Mike Masnick&lt;/a&gt; does a pretty good job describing the situation. The primary takeaways regarding moderation are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Free Speech maximalism continues to be total abject failure&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even if it did work, it proves that the moderation policies in place right now cannot be applied evenly across the entire service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, substack was already in pretty rough moderation straits before, but as the techdirt article linked above states, the Notes feature automatically brings Substack closer to being a typical social media platform, and as a result absolutely MUST moderate in order to maintain its revenue stream. It's clear that Substack isn't prepared for what comes with actually being social media in this way, although I guess I can't say I'm really all that surprised, coming from the team that headed &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.techdirt.com/2021/05/21/content-moderation-case-study-kik-tries-to-get-abuse-under-control-2017/"&gt;Kik Messenger&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="other-glaring-instances"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other Glaring Instances&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously Substack isn't the only offender here. Whilst it's useful as a case study for  implementations and moderation failures as a result of those, I think there are even more mundane systems that attempt to shift into another function and fail, or just don't even try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discord's Forum system, for example, is essentially a real-time chat channel disguised as a
replacement for real forums, which it certainly isn't. Forums are usually indexable and slower-moving, which influences the conversation. Certainly a different &lt;em&gt;era&lt;/em&gt; of design, but not necessarily outdated in regards to conveying information. Discord isn't indexable, which means when those servers inevitably shutdown, all info in those forums goes away permanently. The forum format isn't perfect and has its own share of issues (as well as starting some that continued with modern social media), but a real time chat system is hardly an adequate replacement for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook/Meta is also, as mentioned, the closest possible western analog to a WeChat-like app in this market, and as such also suffers from way... WAY too many issues to count in one blog post like this. Privacy debacles, interoperability issues, moderation missteps...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="please-stop-trying-to-make-everything-apps"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Please Stop Trying To Make Everything Apps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem, I think, is that in the ever-fast-moving era of social media, is that we like having less apps to install, it seems. Gone are the days of 'there's an app for that'. There still is an app for it, but it's been consolidated into like three or four of them instead of ten. I'm not saying there aren't benefits to something like that, but it hardly brings about only positive results, and we're going to have to decide whether it's worth it to have only a couple of applications, companies, and people dictating entire functions of our lives, with all of the moderation, privacy, and ad misery involved with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't have too many explicit solutions, but I do think that there is something to be said for single or dual-purpose applications that don't necessarily involve being 'The App' (singular).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For what people can do personally; Make a blog, make a forum, contribute to whatever you think is worthwhile, but remember:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monoculture kills the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description><category>social media</category><category>sociology</category><category>tech</category><guid>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/on-the-perils-of-everything/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 22:58:23 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>