<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Converging Infinity (Posts about personal)</title><link>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://blog.autumnrain.cc/categories/personal.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2024 &lt;a href="mailto:"&gt;kat&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 06:57:00 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Estradiol Soundsystem</title><link>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/estradiol-soundsystem/</link><dc:creator>kat</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://blog.autumnrain.cc/images/ess.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;p&gt;I honestly expected this to be A) sooner, and B) before the politics post, but neither happened so here we are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start, the blog has been reskinned and the template swapped. The blog should have proper opengraph media previews now! This has been a small but frustrating issue to work through since adding them on bootstrap 4 didn't make them want to play nice with fediverse platforms in particular, and since that's my most likely posting location these days, I wanted them to at least &lt;em&gt;look&lt;/em&gt; pretty. It's also &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; faster since it's not loading a 4k image as the wallpaper (an admittedly rookie mistake), and I'm still thinking about transferring the blog to gitlab or some kind of VPS. This does somewhat mean I need to figure out a new comment system for it, but I'm looking into the viability of the mastodon comments system plugin for Nikola, or the cactus comments system, but I'm not sure how I like having guest accounts comment freely (that typically leads to spam). Or maybe I'll write my own. Who knows. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The major tie-up with the opengraph tags is that I'm more mad that I spent the time on a template, just for a swap to bootblog4 to end up solving most of my issues. I'd like those hours back, please. But no, time moves ever forward. Also I should've just used bootblog4 as a base in the first place, but I digress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like I'm still developing myself as a person, and I think my various writings reflect that. I've recovered a lot from my burnout and am ready to approach things in a more sane and healthy manner. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've started HRT injections in February... Those who know me will know I've been on HRT for a bit but generally not getting much progress in pill form, so we've moved forward a little more. To celebrate this momentous achievement, I accidentally made a fucking awesome album cover and, almost immediately, regretted doing so because of my upcoming foray into music. 
Regardless, doing so made me think about my existence as a trans woman more, because whilst moving towards injections was a MASSIVE thing for me and was worth celebrating, I've had some issues with engaging with family members, now former friends, etc as a result of transitioning in the first place, mostly stemming from political positioning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I'm frustrated, annoyed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I elected to write about some other political frustrations and it went through a few iterations. I can't say the writing is particularly amazing, but it's better than the first draft &lt;em&gt;for sure&lt;/em&gt;. I'm intending to rely less on anecdotes for the next ones, as well, and making them a little more cohesive. So ultimately that's the gist of it all - writing about my perspective on the political system as my whole self&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/estradiol-soundsystem/#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They're all going to take some time, so don't expect a static schedule, but I'll try to aim for like one a month, probably, assuming life doesn't spit in my face again, amongst other things. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone has any comment system suggestions, constructive feedback, etc, it's certainly welcome! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll note quickly that my critique of $political_topic is obviously not representative of every group I'm considered a part of... this is me and me alone. If you gotta criticize anyone about these posts, it's gotta be me and me alone, lol. &lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/estradiol-soundsystem/#fnref:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>blog meta</category><category>personal</category><guid>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/estradiol-soundsystem/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 19:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>