<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Converging Infinity (Posts about projects)</title><link>https://kautumnrain.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://kautumnrain.github.io/categories/projects.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2023 &lt;a href="mailto:"&gt;kat&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 15:27:09 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The Time To Build Is Now</title><link>https://kautumnrain.github.io/posts/reamp/</link><dc:creator>kat</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://kautumnrain.github.io/images/meta.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;p&gt;I tend to say a lot of things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That might seem like an obvious statement to you, but for those that know me well enough, know generally how I feel about the state of the modern web. I am no stranger to loving &lt;a href="https://converginginterests.substack.com/p/second-simple-syndication"&gt;open, interoperable things&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I will admit that generally hating siloes for merely existing is a bit of an old way of thinking, but the game can only be played for so long, and open solutions to modern technological problems require attention in order to be pushed into usable states. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm not a large company. I don't have the millions of dollars of funding to push things into a more usable or covenient state, if those are primary complaints (which we saw with Mastodon). But I will have a little bit of time, a little bit of cash, and a little bit of enthusiasm. To try to build and deploy things. To explore what was lost. To do this in a fun way.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cannot make too many promises now, since I have in the past and I'm realizing that doing so tends to only set me up for failure. What I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; say, is that &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; will come out of it. Even if it's not much, it should be entertaining and interesting, at least for me (:P).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time for talking theoreticals is over; for me, it is time to build. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: Post modified [fixed grammar].&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>dev</category><category>ops</category><category>projects</category><guid>https://kautumnrain.github.io/posts/reamp/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 01:25:41 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>