<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Converging Infinity (Posts about projects)</title><link>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://blog.autumnrain.cc/categories/projects.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2023 &lt;a href="mailto:"&gt;kat&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 21:00:29 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Prelude to Synchronization</title><link>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/prelude-to-sync/</link><dc:creator>kat</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Autumn's here, and that means it's time to iterate harder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typically, I have avoided posting what I do at all outside of a specific thing due to a perceived lack of interest, but Months are actually considerable periods of time when you're doing a lot of waiting, and a lot has been happening recently. From a blog authorship perspective, I'm more realizing at this stage that I just shouldn't care about constantly posting actual interesting things, since that was the pre-switch format in the first place. I simply do not think I'm cut out for content creation in that way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monthly format as of current was actually unintentional: I was between jobs and spiraling pretty hard when I was making those posts. Now the situation has evolved. I am working, but I'm also trying to go back to school, I'm still working on a few projects, and I'm still mostly playing catch-up. My mental energy is definitely pretty low almost all of the time. This being said, however, I believe I have reached a stage where I can start posting somewhat more regularly, even if it's not the most interesting thing in the world. I would generally point out how completely uninteresting I think I am, but I will leave that determination up to the reader. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a fun thing, a couple weeks ago I installed Gentoo on one of my aging laptops and realized the horror and monotony of compiling the GNOME desktop environment on a &lt;a href="https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/products/sku/95443/intel-core-i57200u-processor-3m-cache-up-to-3-10-ghz/specifications.html"&gt;2C4T chip from seven years ago&lt;/a&gt;. Needless to say, I stopped that after awhile and just went with &lt;a href="https://awesomewm.org/"&gt;Awesome&lt;/a&gt;, which I had never tried before and I actually enjoy using. I've been customizing and configuring the machine between sleep and shifts, so the total amount of time I've thrown into it is like maybe a weekend. Though the machine was practically functional after the first couple hours post-install, it was still super fidgety due to the lack of front-ends and etc. I elected, additionally, to customize the bootloader despite the fact that I find it more or less unnecessary - I had actually never done it before and it was &lt;em&gt;somewhat&lt;/em&gt; painless except for one absolutely annoying thing: grub hates most of the fonts I throw at it, and it looks... dire. I am looking for some fonts to throw at it that aren't totally butchered by &lt;code&gt;grub2-mkfont&lt;/code&gt; but it's frankly been taking more time than I really want to throw at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an aside, I have swapped to &lt;a href="https://opentofu.org/"&gt;OpenTofu&lt;/a&gt; for provisioning now that it's available, and I'm pleased that my previous TF files are just drop-in, for now. I look forward to see where it goes from here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the Gentoo laptop, I had another go at installing OpenBSD on a VM because the last time I did, it was quirky and on hardware that was incredibly aged. This was fine, actually,  but it wasn't really usable as a proper client machine at the time. The main thing I learned from it was that the install is easier than I remember and XFCE is actually super easy to customize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have some things to do, namely some blog customization stuff (I'm trying to figure out a way to add fields in some areas which isn't super hard, but I want it broken out to a markdown meta header...), I have a laptop I'm eyeing to replace my ever-aging Thinkpad T460 as my main "go box" for school, and I'm still dinking around with the Jabber protocol, albeit slowly. I'm also trying to decide whether or not I should make a new theme for both my website and blog (for parity) since it was about this time last year that I updated it. As such, a follow-up will be forthcoming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay warm out there.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>blog meta</category><category>dev</category><category>ops</category><category>projects</category><guid>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/prelude-to-sync/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Optical Simulacra, Changing Perspectives</title><link>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/optical-simulacra/</link><dc:creator>kat</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Finally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting the spare time to write has been generally pretty challenging. Work itself generally eats up my entire weekend, but I actually got out early today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working third shift and permanently detonating my sleep schedule has given me a bizzare perspective. I'm one of those people who tends to go on really, &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; long walks to get some exercise and reset myself, and doing it at three in the morning adds onto the weirdness. Put simply, the world just isn't designed to operate at night. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in that silence there are still things that reveal themselves. As an example, I rather like the night sky, what little of it can be seen from my neck of the woods. For a long time, I wished to do astrophotography. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modern phone cameras are... interesting. I happen to have a Google Pixel 6 as my daily driver, and overall the phone has treated me well as... my phone. Very rarely do I take pictures with it, because the camera is oft an added bonus, not my make-or-break feature. 
This being said, of course the first thing I do with it is take some pictures of various things, including but not limited to, cats, flowers, and autumn leaves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having had the phone for a bit and being up at ohgodthirty, I elected to take one of my walks. The route is pretty contrived, but it passes near a couple of cell phone towers. So as I pass by one, I take a picture of it flashing, in the ever-lasting silence of the night. After I let the phone do the long exposure, I review the image. I will not be posting the image for various reasons, but overall: the night sky glistens with the stars in the sky, the tower glows with the bright red of its beacons, and I have this... godawful feeling mixed with awe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that I can take pictures at night isn't what bothers me... I guess it's more that the image feels phony. I, with the convenience of modern processing, have just taken a picture that probably was barely possible with the mobile hardware, 5-10 years ago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allow me to explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When looking at a real, modern camera™, there are several components absolutely necessary to take an image. First, you have your camera sensor, generally comprised of tiny capacitors (if you're stuck in CCD land), or tiny photodiodes and transistors, and you have your lens. The lens is the major thing here, because for me this is why this image feels fake: A phone essentially has to emulate, with the best of its ability, a full optical assembly. This can only realistically be done with a &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/how-do-smartphone-cameras-work/"&gt;lens stack in tandem with software processing&lt;/a&gt;, and whilst raw images are possible at 1x from &lt;a href="https://hoagonsight.com/the-pixel-7-cameras-overprocessing-and-image-distortion-problems-why-they-occur/"&gt;certain anecdotes&lt;/a&gt;, it appears that the Pixel 6 itself tends to overprocess anything beyond that. Which is... frankly kind of an issue when you're using supposedly &lt;a href="https://www.tomsguide.com/reviews/google-pixel-6"&gt;one of the best cameras on the market&lt;/a&gt;. I will take this opportunity to say that it's not innately a 'bad camera'-- Moreso that the processing is definitely present, and I've noticed it more the more images I've shot with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So already, an SLR camera is a simulacrum of an optic nerve, but adding layers ontop, we have a &lt;em&gt;simulacrum of a simulacrum&lt;/em&gt;. Yes, this conjunction of words feels like utter nonsense (especially because, despite the fact that I have indeed read &lt;em&gt;Simulacra and Simulation&lt;/em&gt; by Jean Baudrillard, he thought people were taking the orders too seriously so it's difficult to take the source text too seriously as a result of that), but it's given me a lot to think about. In a sense, it seemed a lot like everything around me was stained the same color-- That everything around me was fake and ephemeral; We already live in a world where LLMs have poisoned practically everything, and 'AI art' models (GANs?) have finally started making perceptible images, at the cost of being really shitty to artists trying to make a living... as a result of that, this feeling didn't go away, literally at all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So naturally, I dug up a film camera from my late stepfather's things, and am being lent a DSLR. At first I just had the film camera with some Ilford HP5+, but the digital camera came into being when I realized how completely unforgiving film is to learn on, which I actually like and am still using it for. But I can refine my skill more if I have, frankly, a cheaper method of learning. Enter: &lt;a href="https://www.nikonusa.com/en/nikon-products/product-archive/dslr-cameras/d60.html"&gt;The Nikon D60&lt;/a&gt;. It isn't full frame, but I don't mind at all. As you can see down below, with the image of the cat, it takes a pretty decent picture still!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://autumnrain.cc/images/DSC_0037.JPG" width="500" alt="Master Samwise, an orange and white cat, after eating some grass" style="align: center;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people like the convenience of the modern smartphone, and that's totally OK, but I think I'll take the D60 around with me for awhile, and take some pictures that, at the least, feel just that &lt;em&gt;tiny bit&lt;/em&gt; more real. Even if there's a little bit more effort involved.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>hobbies</category><category>photography</category><category>projects</category><category>ramblings</category><guid>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/optical-simulacra/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 09:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Status Update Zone</title><link>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/the-status-update-zone-July-7th/</link><dc:creator>kat</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://blog.autumnrain.cc/images/gestalt1.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;p&gt;The title says it all, basically. I dunno how often these will even be necessary, but I've definitely put myself in a corner with how I'm handling the actual blogging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I'm working on getting my old substack content off of the platform and put here. Once this is done, it'll be under the 'digest-archive' category. It is far
past time I stopped relying on that platform for hosting any of my content. The posts will be properly backdated, and all links will be replaced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been roughly a year since I tried to do a weekly arrangement of interesting things, and since then, 
I've burnt out probably three times over and have gone through multiple life-changing events.  I'm slowly getting my groove properly again, 
but I'm still finding it pretty difficult to do things efficiently as of yet. Recovery has been... challenging. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although some things, including some inconsistent applications of certain CSS frameworks on the static HTML
and a haphazard workflow between machines continue to pose some challenges, I don't necessarily find it inconvenient to manage the blog in this way. 
I still find the challenge to be in the writing, and I know I'm not exactly a good author. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been mostly avoiding posting on social media for a hot while, but especially the last couple of weeks... I don't think people want to hear my incessant sadposting about my trivial problems
(and, of course, complaining about it online does nothing for me), so I will keep it to myself, for now. Additionally, with platforms enshittifying extremely fast, I find that navigating all of it,
even with filters, to be incredibly draining. I am not a good litmus test for opinions on these things, so I will not preoffer them here (despite already doing so, basically).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the previous post, I have started on a set of scripts for the Jabber/XMPP protocol. I don't have much more than boilerplate code at present, but I'm hoping to improve the seemingly-dire
script/bot/daemon landscape a little at a time. The major issue appears to be a lack of ready-made API wrappers for some things, but I'm not that worried about it. 
If required, I will design wrappers from scratch, although I cannot promise I will do that consistently. A lot of it has been documentation, research, and planning, 
but I find all three are incredibly important for being able to do anything of note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy (Belated) Pride Month*, and hopefully y'all are living your best lives. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*(Pride Month never stops :P)&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>projects</category><category>ramblings</category><guid>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/the-status-update-zone-July-7th/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 07:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Time To Build Is Now</title><link>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/reamp/</link><dc:creator>kat</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://blog.autumnrain.cc/images/meta.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;p&gt;I tend to say a lot of things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That might seem like an obvious statement to you, but for those that know me well enough, know generally how I feel about the state of the modern web. I am no stranger to loving &lt;a href="https://converginginterests.substack.com/p/second-simple-syndication"&gt;open, interoperable things&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I will admit that generally hating siloes for merely existing is a bit of an old way of thinking, but the game can only be played for so long, and open solutions to modern technological problems require attention in order to be pushed into usable states. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- TEASER_END --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm not a large company. I don't have the millions of dollars of funding to push things into a more usable or covenient state, if those are primary complaints (which we saw with Mastodon). But I will have a little bit of time, a little bit of cash, and a little bit of enthusiasm. To try to build and deploy things. To explore what was lost. To do this in a fun way.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cannot make too many promises now, since I have in the past and I'm realizing that doing so tends to only set me up for failure. What I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; say, is that &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; will come out of it. Even if it's not much, it should be entertaining and interesting, at least for me (:P).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time for talking theoreticals is over; for me, it is time to build. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes: Post modified [fixed grammar].&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>dev</category><category>ops</category><category>projects</category><guid>https://blog.autumnrain.cc/posts/reamp/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 01:25:41 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>